Guide to the Malawi Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Malawi collection
1937-2013
MS 1528
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.27
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political, economic, and social conditions in Malawi.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political, economic, and social conditions in Malawi.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Malawi -- Description and travel; Malawi -- Economic conditions; Malawi -- History -- 1953-1964; Malawi -- History -- 1964-1994; Malawi -- Politics and government; Malawi -- Social life and customs; Banda, H. Kamuzu (Hastings Kamuzu), -1997; Alliance for Democracy
- Inventory, 1959-1993
  - English colonial documents concerning Nyasaland, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Periodicals, 1960-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Business and industry: information booklets; journals; reports, 1968-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Banda, H. Kamuzu, President of the Republic of Malawi: speeches; biographical material, 1968-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anniversary of Independence: tenth, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - Academic journals; newsletters; printed material, 1977-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Additional Material, 1937-1998; Accession 1995-M-149
  - Additional printed materials, 1937-1939, 1947, 1951, 1958-1963, 1992-1998, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, 1970-1999; Accession 2004-M-077
  - "Odi, bilingual quarterly of Malawian writing", 1973 October (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Malawi Congress Party (MCP) election material and photograph, 1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Research Committee Report to Senate," University of Malawi, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, 1991-2004; Accession 2010-M-110
  Scope and Contents
  The material is arranged as received.
  - The Kamba: newsletter of the Centre for Human Rigbts and Rehabilitation, 1991, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Official guide to the 2004 Malawi General Election (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AFSC Africa Report, American Friends Service Committee, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chipulumutso PPM Newsletter, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Voterani Gwanda" campaign poster, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "AFORD" campaign sticker, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1964-2000s; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1964-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, 2000s (Folder 3, Box 2, Folder 1)